propertyline.ca 2018-03-19

# Privacy Statement | MPAC

## Privacy Policy

The Municipal Property Assessment Corporation (MPAC) is committed to protecting your privacy.  We manage the collection, retention and dissemination of personal and non-personal information in compliance with the requirements of the [_Municipal Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act_](https://www.ontario.ca/laws/statute/90m56 "link to municipal freedom of information and protection of privacy act"), the [_Assessment Act_](https://www.ontario.ca/laws/statute/90a31 "link to assessment act at ontario government website") and other applicable legislation, regulations and judicial and quasi-judicial rulings.

## How MPAC Protects your Privacy

MPAC does not release personal information (i.e., recorded information about an identifiable individual), or any other data that would divulge an individual’s identity, except where required or permitted by law, or by court order. While MPAC may release aggregate information in the form of demographic studies constructed from the analysis of personal information, these studies do not identify individuals. Further, MPAC does not release actual income or expense information except where legally required or permitted to do so, or by court order.

Personal information that is stored and processed on MPAC’s information systems is protected by industry standard security, firewalls, password and user authentication, and encryption technology, as necessary. Only authorized persons may access MPAC’s information systems as required by their job responsibilities and only within the scope of administering legally authorized activities.  MPAC’s web services use high level secure socket layer (SSL) encryption that protects your personal information while in transit. MPAC’s technology safeguards are comparable to those used by leading financial institutions and government agencies. Any violation of MPAC’s privacy or security policies will result in swift and appropriate action, which may include referring violations to law enforcement authorities or the Information and Privacy Commissioner of Ontario, or disciplinary action against the individual(s) responsible for the violation.

While delivering services to you, we may contract with third-party service providers that operate either in Canada or in the continental United States.  We will only contract with reputable firms that adhere to strict privacy and security standards. While information may reside with or be processed by third-party service providers, MPAC requires that all service providers have similar levels of privacy and security as would apply to MPAC’s own information systems.

## External Links

There are websites linked to and from this site that are created and/or operated by third-party organizations.  Those organizations are solely responsible for the operation of the website and the information contained on the website, including the legal right to publicly display such information. MPAC provides links to or from third-party websites as a convenience only and such links do not constitute any endorsement of the third-party or guarantee of any information on the website.  Further, those linked websites may or may not be available in French and/or be accessible to persons with disabilities.

MPAC will not be liable in any way whatsoever for providing any link to any third-party website, the operation, content or the right to display such information of any of the linked websites, nor for any of the information, interpretation, comments or opinions expressed in any of the linked websites. Any comments or inquiries regarding the linked websites are to be directed to the organization that operates the particular website.

## Use of Cookies

Some parts of this website may use cookies to help personalize your online experience. A cookie is a text file that is saved to your computing device by a webserver. Cookies provide a convenience feature to save you time. They tell the webserver that you have returned to a specific page which helps MPAC recall your specific information on subsequent visits to this site. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. Cookies are uniquely assigned to your web session and can only be read by a webserver in the domain that issued the cookie to you. MPAC does not use cookies for logging statistical information for site usage reports, nor does MPAC save or store personal information in cookies.

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can configure your browser setting to decline cookies. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to access some of the features or services on our website. Most web browsers also offer the ability to delete cookies during or after your web session.

## Collection and Use of Personal Information

MPAC is committed to excellence in program delivery and strives to provide you with the most efficient services while protecting your privacy and meeting its statutory obligations.  MPAC will only collect and use personal information that is absolutely necessary to deliver legally authorized programs and services.  On occasion, MPAC may also use this information to conduct surveys, obtain feedback and enhance the delivery of these same programs and services.

MPAC is responsible for administering a uniform and province-wide property assessment system based on current value assessment under the _Assessment Act_ ; identifying potential jurors for the Ministry of the Attorney General under the _Juries Act_ ; identifying municipal, school board and District Social Services Administration Board electors and producing the Preliminary Lists of Electors under the _Municipal Elections Act_ , 1996; identifying all school supporters in Ontario under the _Assessment Act_ and the _Education Act_ ; and, producing the Ontario Population Report required for administering the _Health Protection and Promotion Act_ , the _Education Act_ and the _Police Services Act_.  MPAC is also required to provide electoral information to Elections Ontario and Elections Canada.

## **Telephone and Email Contact**

Except where you may have ongoing business dealings with an MPAC official on a specific matter, MPAC does not collect personal information by telephone or email in the ordinary course of business.  Accordingly, you should never provide personal information in response to a telephone caller that claims to be an MPAC employee or representative nor should you reply to any unsolicited email that purports to have been sent from MPAC.

## Have Questions

If you have any questions or require further information about how MPAC protects your privacy, please contact MPAC’s Privacy Officer at (905) 837-6188 or 1-877-635-6722 ext. 6188

Note: The applicable law prevails to the extent there is any conflict between this information and the current law. This information is not intended to provide legal advice and should not be relied upon as such.
